Rory Harder

AOS Philosophy of Language, Philosophy of Mind AOC Epistemology (including formal), Logic

Academic Employment

2021–2022 Postdoctoral Fellow, University of Toronto 2019–2021 Part Time Lecturer, Rutgers University

Education

GRADUATE

2015–2022 PHD in Philosophy, University of Toronto, ABD

Dissertation Title: Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Co-Supervisors: Imogen Dickie and Nate Charlow

Expected Defense: January 2022

VISITING STUDENT in Linguistics, Rutgers University

Host Supervisor: Simon Charlow

Undergraduate

2012–2015 BA (Hons) with High Distinction in Philosophy (Specialist) and History and Philoso-

phy of Science and Technology (Minor), University of Toronto

2011–2012 Trent University

Papers

[A paper on the formal semantics of demonstratives]

Revise and Resubmit

[A paper on joint attention]

Revise and Resubmit

Understanding Demonstratives Together

In Preparation

Presentations

	Refereed
2021	Joint Attention: The Window Into Other Minds? American Philosophical Association (APA) Pacific D
	Joint Attention and Communication

sophical Association (APA) Pacific Division Meeting (Symposium)

Joint Attention and Communication Mutual Knowledge 40 Workshop

A Puzzle About Demonstrative Understanding

PhiLang 2021

Perspectives in Demonstrative Semantics 2020

WeSSLLI Student Session; Szklarska Poreba Workshop

The Affiliative Conception of Sense 2019

Communication, Context, Conversation Workshop

Clearing up Clouds

APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium)

Clearing up Clouds 2018

2017

2019

Context, Cognition, and Communication Conference

Inferences and Neutrality of the Deliberative Ought

APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium); Canadian Philosophical Association Meeting

INVITED

The Grammar of Reference 2020

New York Philosophy of Language Workshop

Inferences and Neutrality of the Deliberative Ought 2017

> Semantics Research Group (University of Toronto Department of Linguistics); Computational Linguistics Seminar (University of Toronto Department of Computer Science)

Teaching

Course Instructorships at Rutgers University

Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year, Online) 2020

Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year)

Course Instructorships at the University of Toronto

Special Topics in Philosophy: Frege's Puzzle (3rd year, Online) 2020

Issues in Philosophy of Mind: Perception and Conception (3rd year) 2019

> Rory Harder 2

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIPS AT THE UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Ancient Philosophy (2nd year), 17th- and 18th-Century Philosophy (2nd year), Introduction to Philosophy (1st year), Knowledge and Reality (2nd year), Probability and Inductive Logic (2nd year), Introduction to Symbolic Logic (2nd year, online)

OTHER

Super-TA for the Socrates Project (Supervising Undergraduate TAs, University of Toronto)
Philosophy Don (Tutor and Residence Assistant, Trinity College, University of Toronto)

Scholarships & Awards

GRADUATE

2020–2021 Doctoral Completion Award (\$14,859)

Merit-based award for graduate students at the University of Toronto.

2019–2020 Ontario Graduate Scholarship (\$15,000)

Merit-based scholarship for graduate students at public universities in Ontario.

SSHRC CGS Michael Smith Foreign Study Supplement (\$6,000)

Awarded annually to 125 Canadian graduate students in the social sciences and humanities.

2016–2019 SSHRC Joseph-Armand Bombardier CGS Doctoral Scholarship (\$105,000)

Awarded to about 22% of applicants, who are Canadian graduate students in the social sciences and humanities.

Undergraduate

2012

The George Kennedy Scholarship, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto Awarded annually to a graduating philosophy student.

Socrates Award, Department of Philosophy, Trent University

Awarded annually to a philosophy student in each of the second and third years.

Professional Activity

Graduate Student Coordinator for Institutional Strategic Initiative in Language and Cognition, University of Toronto

ATTENDEE at 29th European Summer School in Logic, Language, and Information
ATTENDEE at Seventh North American Summer School on Logic, Language, and Information

Referee and Commentater for Philosophy Graduate Student Conference, University of Toronto

Rory Harder 3

Dissertation

Title

Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Summary

My dissertation develops a view of human communication, as a refinement of the Gricean orthodoxy, according to which it is the essentially joint activity of making sense of one another's actions. I begin by motivating my view on the basis of recent work on joint attention. I then discuss the distinctiveness of linguistic communication, and elaborate the Chomskean view that it involves the deployment of autonomous linguistic competence. The general considerations about communication and language are then applied to the meaning and use of demonstratives. I provide a formal semantics for demonstratives in the dynamic tradition, as I argue that dynamic semantics is a component of linguistic competence. Finally, I draw on that semantics and the overarching refined Gricean view of communication in order to solve two old puzzles about what demonstrative understanding requires.

References

Research

IMOGEN DICKIE, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: imogen.dickie@utoronto.ca

NATE CHARLOW, Associate Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: nate.charlow@utoronto.ca

PHILIP KREMER, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: philip.kremer@utoronto.ca

CHRIS BARKER, Professor, Department of Linguistics, New York University

Contact: Chris.Barker@nyu.edu

Teaching

RACHEL BARNEY, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: rachel.barney@utoronto.ca

Contact Information

E-mail rory.harder@mail.utoronto.ca https://www.roryharder.com

Address Philosophy Department, 170 St. George St., Toronto, ON, Canada M5R 2M8

Rory Harder 4